Finding Aid for the Lloyd E. Cotsen Cuneiform Tablets Collection LSC.1883
UCLA Library Special Collections
- School text, lexical exercise of personal names., Old Babylonian Period (c. 1900-1600 BCE); SC-IV-5; Obverse 1. …; 2. …; 3. 'Servant of the sun god'; 4. 'His servant'; 5. …; 6. 'Servant of Lamma'; 7. 'Servant of Kalkal'; 8. 'Servant of Kala'; 9. 'Servant of the moon god'; 10. 'Servant of Ishtaran'; 11. 'Hero'; 12. 'Servant of Sagku'; 13. …; 14. …; 15. …; 16. …; 17. …; 18. 'Servant of the big brother'; Reverse 1. 'Servant of the brother of An'; 2. …; 3. 'Servant of his brother'; 4. …; 5. …; 6. …; 7. 'Sweet servant of the prince'; 8. …; 9. …; 10. 'His servant'; 11. …; 12. 'Little servant'; 13. 'The littlest servant'; 14. 'Servant of the scepter'; 15. …; 16. 'Servant of the man'; 17. …; 18. …; 4 1/8" height x 2 1/2" width x 7/8" depth, rectangular double column tablet with one column shaved down; Rectangular tablet with losses at two corners. The surface at these losses is jagged and uneven. There are a number of incomplete cracks, particularly along two of the edges. Some of these cracks are covered with a clear adhesive. Half of the tablet is about 1/8" thinner than the other half. This appears to have been done when the clay was still wet because there is cuneiform script on this thinner portion overall. There are several white concretions visible overall. (Drawer 3)